magcloud.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy. Book publishing services | Blurb Books | Blurb

Effective Date: 05/25/18

Blurb, Inc, a company incorporated in Delaware (File Number 3949786) and located at 580 California Street, Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94104, United States ("Blurb", "us" or "we") respects the privacy of the visitors to its Website located at [https://www.blurb.com](https://www.blurb.com/) (the "Website"), and users of its Services. This Privacy Policy informs you of our policies and practices regarding the collection, use, storage and disclosure of any Personal Information and Anonymous Information you submit to us through the Website or Services. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Blurb. Unless otherwise defined herein, capitalized terms shall have the meanings assigned to such terms set forth in the Blurb Terms and Conditions that you can find at Terms and Conditions and which incorporate this Privacy Policy by reference.

"Personal Information" is any information that allows us (or others) to identify an individual person and would include (for example) your name, address, email address, IP Address or phone number, as well as other non-public information that is associated with or directly linked to such information.

An "Internet protocol address" or "IP Address" is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases, your IP Address stays the same from browser session to browser session; but if you use a consumer Internet access provider, your IP Address probably varies from session to session. We track IP Addresses solely in conjunction with session Cookies to analyze our web page flow and to determine the appropriate language settings for you based on your region if you did not previously indicate. You can find out more about the Cookies and other tracking technologies that we use and the purposes for which we use them in the section below headed 'Cookies'.

"Anonymous Information" means information or a combination of information that does not relate to or identify individual persons.

We collect and use Personal Information and Anonymous Information as described in this Privacy Policy. We respect your right to privacy and will only process Personal Information (including any sensitive personal data) you provide us in accordance with all applicable privacy laws.

### User Consent

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By accessing and using our Website and Services, you agree to be legally bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. In addition, for certain activities on the Website, we may further confirm your consent by asking you to expressly consent to the collection, processing, storage and use of your Personal Information according to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please refrain from using our Website or accessing our Services.

### International Transfers

**Your Personal Information will be processed by Blurb, Inc., and other third party data processors for the purposes identified and described in this Privacy Policy only.**

**By accessing or using our Website or Services or otherwise providing Personal Information to us, you consent to the processing, transfer and storage of your information in and to the United States for these purposes only. Please be aware that countries, which are located outside the EEA, may not offer the same level of data protection as countries located in the EEA, although our collection, storage and use of your Personal Information will continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy.**

Blurb, Inc. complies with the General Data Protection Regulation (the "GDPR"). Blurb also complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Blurb, Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about GDPR, please visit <https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/data-protection/legislation/history-general-data-protection-regulation_en>. For more information on the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

Blurb, as a "Data Controller" is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives from users of its websites and services, under the GDPR and Privacy Shield Frameworks. Blurb may subsequently transfer personal data to third parties acting as an agent on its behalf ("Data Processors"). Blurb complies with the GDPR and Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Swiss individuals, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Blurb is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Blurb may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

You may revoke your consent at any time by contacting Blurb (address below) or by deleting the Personal Information you have submitted through our Website or Services.

### Collection of Personal Information

The Personal Information we gather from you helps us learn about your visit to the Website or use of the Services. We use this information to provide the Services to you, to better tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services, to answer your requests, questions and concerns, and to offer you additional information and opportunities.

### Personal Information You Provide to Us

We collect Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily through our Website or Services.

  * When you register on the Website, we will collect your full name and username, a password, and an email address. We use these data to create your account and to provide the Services to you.
  * When you use the Service, we collect your user ID, email address and IP address. We also collect your social security number (SSN) or tax identification number (TIN) (which ever is applicable) specifically for our Set Your Profit (SYP) program. We collect this information to better tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services.
  * When you create your profile on the Website after registering, we will collect on an optional basis other Personal Information, such as information about your hobbies, interests, additional contact information, etc. You do not have to provide this additional information but if you do, we will use this information to better tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services.
  * When you order products or services on the Website, we will collect all information necessary to complete the transaction, including your name, credit card information, billing information and shipping information.
  * When you subscribe to a Blurb newsletter, we will collect your email address to provide you with promotional information about our services where you have agreed to receive such communications. You may unsubscribe from the newsletter service at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the newsletter you receive or by contacting us.
  * When you contact us to submit comments, questions or feedback using the forms on the Website or in the Services, we will collect your name, email address and your comment, question or feedback to answer your request, questions or concerns.
  * When you voluntarily participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information such as demographic information. We use this information to better tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services.
  * When you use the "Save Contacts" function to save e-mail addresses to which you have sent announcements, we will collect and store such e-mail addresses.
  * When you contact us using the request forms on the Website or in the Services, we will collect your name, email address and your comment or question that you enter into the form to answer your request, questions or concerns.
  * When you post messages on the message boards of the Website or through the Services, the information contained in your posting will be stored on our servers and made public so other users will be able to see it.
  * When you contact us by sending us an email, we will collect and store your email address and any information contained in the email you send us and any information attached to the email for so long as is necessary. This information is used to answer your email and address any questions and concerns you may have.

We may also collect, from you, the following personal information about your contacts:

  * Name and address of a gift recipient, in order to fulfill a purchase order

When you provide us with personal information about your contacts we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided.

If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [support@blurb.com](mailto:support@blurb.com).

Please note that Content that you use for your Books or that you contribute to other Members for their Books might also contain Personal Information. Please be mindful that such Content may be made available to others (including through the use of the Book preview functionality) as content of your Books or the Books of other Members to which you contributed Content and that you therefore should only use and contribute Content that you are comfortable sharing under these conditions and for which you have obtained (where applicable) all necessary and valid consents to share and disclose such Content.

### Personal Information Collected Via the Service Platform

Blurb collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients.

### Personal Information Collected Via Tracking Technology

As you navigate our Website or App, certain information may also be passively collected, including your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, operating system, mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity. We also use Cookies and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the solutions and information for which you searched and which you viewed. This type of information is collected to analyze the use of our Services and solutions and to make them more useful to you. Like other aspects of our Services, we use a third party service provider for some or all of this type of data collection and analysis. These third party service providers may also independently collect information about you as described in "Disclosure of Personal Information" below. For more detailed information about Cookies and other online tracking tools that we use and the purposes for which we use them, please see our section below headed "Cookies".

### Personal Information We Receive From Other Sources

We may receive Personal Information about you from other sources like mobile device, telephone or fax or from companies that provide our services by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website ("Partner Companies"), and for some of our Services, this includes location based services applicable for certain features in the Services. If you choose to disable location based services some features of the Services may not work properly. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our Website or Services in order to improve the products and services we provide.

### Use of Information

In general, Personal Information you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. We may also use your Personal Information to, provide you with the Blurb newsletters, surveys, or promotional emails regarding changes and upgrades to our products and services and for other marketing purposes of Blurb or our partners, should you request and consent to receive such communications from us. For more information about how to change your preferences and to unsubscribe from promotional communications, please see the section below headed "Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information".

We may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the information personally identifiable to you. We may use this Anonymous Information to analyze request patterns and usage patterns so that we may enhance our products and services. We may disclose this Anonymous Information to third parties contracted by Blurb to provide marketing services designed to promote our products and services. Blurb reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Information to third parties in its discretion.

### Feedback

If you provide feedback on any of our products and services to us, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided we will not associate such feedback with your Personal Information. Blurb will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the Personal Information in such communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Disclosure of Personal Information

Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not trade, rent, or share your Personal Information with third parties and we will not disclose financial information that is part of your Personal Information unless you ask us to do so.

We may share your Personal Information with third parties to provide you with the products and services that we offer you through the Website or Services for payment processing, shipping and distribution processing, account inquiries, and marketing analytics. These third parties are required not to use your Personal Information other than to provide the products and services requested by Blurb and are bound by confidentiality agreements with regard to their use of such information. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Information with our contractors and third-party service providers ("Data Processors") for the sole purpose of providing products and services to you.

If you use the Book Preview functionality of the Services, any Personal Information contained in the Book Content of the Book(s) for which you have selected Book Preview will be made publicly available to visitors of the Website, including search engines.

We may enter into co-branding or co-promotional agreements with third parties pursuant to which we may share Personal Information with such third parties. For example, we may enter into agreements with Partner Companies pursuant to which we provide the Partner Companies with a URL and a customer registration page co-branded with, or private labeled by, the Partner Companies, and the Partner Companies distributes and promotes the URL to its customers. A Partner Company may have access to Personal Information that we collect from their customers. As a result, if you register on the Website or use our Services through a Partner Company, we may provide your Personal Information to the Partner Company. Please note, however, that we do not control the privacy practices of these third parties.

If another company acquires our company or our assets, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Information (as described below), we may disclose your Personal Information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Blurb; (b) to protect and defend the rights or property of Blurb or users of our Services; or (c) lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### Your Privacy Rights

Upon request Blurb will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging in to your account and updating your personal information and confirming it by selecting the ‘Save’ button, contacting us at [support@blurb.com](mailto:support@blurb.com), or by completing this form. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

Blurb acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Blurb has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the Blurb Client Support at [support@blurb.com](mailto:support@blurb.com). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client.

You have the right to access information held about you. Any access request may be subject to a fee of $10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. You also have the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personally identifiable information that we hold about you free of charge.

In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information, or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.

### Cookies and Tracking Technologies

Blurb and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the Website, track users’ movements around the Website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our Website or service.

We may use Cookies to collect information about you.

### **_What is a cookie?_**

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that a web site sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a web site. For example, we may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on the Website or Services. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, some areas of the Website or Services may not work properly. We encode our Cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them. For more information about removing or rejecting Cookies, please see "Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information" below.

Blurb may also collect information via clear gifs or web beacons (also known as "tracking pixels") that help us better manage content on Website and Services by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to Cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to Cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages.

### **_How do we use cookies?_**

Cookies do lots of different jobs on our Website, such as letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, remembering your email and password, letting us analyze how well our Website is performing, and improving your experience. They also help ensure that advertisements you see whilst you are on our Website are more relevant to you and your interests

### **_What cookies do we use?_**

Below we have provided a list of the categories of Cookies found on our Website, and a description of what those Cookies do. Some of these Cookies are essential to the operation of our Services. Others are not essential, but help to improve our Website by collecting [anonymous] user information, or try and improve your experience of our Website by remembering your choices. We also use cookies, which collect information about your browsing habits in order to try, and display advertising, which is relevant to you and your interests.

We use the following types of Cookies:

**Stricly Necessary Cookies** We use a number of Cookies, which are essential to the operation of our Website and Services. For example, these types of Cookies enable you to log into secure areas of the Services, provide the necessary security when you access our Website or Services, and help ensure the content of the pages you request load quickly. Without these cookies, services that you have asked for cannot be provided.

**Functional Cookies:** Functional Cookies are ones that we set to help the Services work the way you expect them to. Some Cookies are necessary to enable you to move around our Website and/or to use the Services. Without these Cookies, we can't provide the Services you have asked for, like processing payments made via our online store.

We use other Cookies to help recognize and remember you when you are logged into our Services so we can remember your settings and preferences, such as your language and region or logged in state. These Cookies also may help us provide services you have asked for.

As described below, you may disable any of these functional Cookies; but if you do so, then various functions of the Services may be unavailable to you or may not work the way you want them to.

### Performance and Analytical Cookies:

### _Advertising and Web Analytic Tools_

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

We use third-party advertising and/or web analytics companies to serve ads and/or to provide us web analytics when you visit our Website or Services. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites (e.g., through the use of Cookies) in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you, to provide us analyses of how our Website is used. Although we do not authorize these third parties to collect your Personal Information from our Website or Services, they may associate data collected about your use of our Website or Services with the Personal Information they have collected about you from other websites.

For more information about third-party advertising and how to exercise your choices regarding advertising customization by third-party ad networks on our Services, visit the Network Advertising Initiative's website here.

**_Google Analytics_** Our Website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses Cookies to help the Website analyze how users use the Website and Services. The information generated by the Cookie about your use of the Website and Services will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.

In case IP-anonymization is activated on this website, your IP Address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP Address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymization is active on this Website.

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this Website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to Website activity and Internet usage.

The IP Address that your Browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on for your current web browser: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

For further information please visit:

  * <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>
  * <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

### Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information

We offer you the following choices regarding the collection, storage, use, and sharing of your Personal Information:

**Promotional Communications:** You have the right to ask us not to process Personal Information for marketing or promotional purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. When you receive promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the communication you receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below). Despite your indicated preferences, we may still send you non-promotional communications regarding the services we provide to you, such as transaction reports, and notices regarding changes to the Website or Services. In any case we may send updates to our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy or other policies.

**Cookies:** Most web browsers are set to accept Cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser Cookies.

### Managing Cookies

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.

Here’s how to do it:

  * Google Chrome 
    * In the settings menu, select 'show advanced settings' at the bottom of the page.
    * Select the 'content settings' button in the privacy section.
    * The top section of the page that then appears tells you about cookies and allows you to set the cookies you want. It also allows you to clear any cookies currently stored.
  * Mozilla Firefox 
    * In the tools menu, select 'options' (MAC users, go to the Firefox menu select ‘preferences’)
    * Select the privacy tab in the options box.
    * From the dropdown choose, 'use custom settings for history'. This will bring up the options for cookies and you can choose to enable or disable them by clicking the tickbox.
  * Internet Explorer 6+ 
    * In the tools menu, select 'Internet options'.
    * Click the privacy tab.
    * You will see a privacy settings slider which has six settings that allow you to control the number of cookies that will be placed: Block All Cookies, High, Medium High, Medium (default level), Low, and Accept All Cookies.
  * Safari browser 
    * In the settings menu / Safari menu, select the 'preferences' option.
    * Open the privacy tab.
    * Select the option you want from the 'block cookies' section.
  * All other browsers 
    * For information on how to manage cookies via other browsers, please consult your documentation or online help files.

Please note that if you choose to remove or reject Cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of the Services. For further information about cookies, including how to refuse Cookies, please visit www.allaboutcookies.org .You may change any of the Personal Information in your account by editing your online profile or by sending an email to us at the email address set forth below.

**Behavioral Advertising Targeting:** We partner with a third party to display advertising on the Website and to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union click [here.](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

If you would like to opt out of third-party advertising behavior collection and use from your use of our Website, you may do so via the Network Advertising Initiative at <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

Please note that if you choose to turn off behavioral advertising it does not mean you will no longer receive advertising on the Services. However, it does mean that the display advertising that you use may not be tailored to your likely interests of preferences on the web browser you are currently using. Using this tool only applies to online behavioral advertising and will not affect other services.

### Regarding Minors

If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Information to us, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information and terminate the child's account from our databases. We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors who are under the age of 13.

### Other Sites

Our provision of a link to any other website or location is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites.

### Mobile Application

When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID").

We do not ask you for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or services.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile app.

### Security

Blurb is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Information. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized or unlawful access, use, or disclosure and against accidental loss or destruction of, or damage to, such Personal Information.

Blurb has implemented industry-standard electronic means of protecting your Personal Information. We store Personal Information behind a computer firewall, a barrier designed to prevent outsiders from accessing our servers, and we have implemented technology to detect intrusions. We also require you to enter a password to access your account information. In addition, Blurb protects your Personal Information from unauthorized physical access by storing your Personal Information in a controlled facility.

Except as provided elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, Blurb limits access to Personal Information in electronic databases to those persons (including employees and contractors) in Blurb’s organization who have a business need for such access. Lastly, we conduct periodic internal audits and vulnerability scans to ensure compliance with these security measures and generate security incident logs that track Information useful in screening for attempted abuse of or unauthorized access to your Personal Information.

Even though Blurb has taken significant steps to ensure that your Personal Information is not intercepted, accessed, used, or disclosed by unauthorized persons, you should know that Blurb cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at support@blurb.com.

### Contact Us

Should you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us through Customer Support or:

Blurb, Inc.  
Attention: Legal Department  
580 California Street, Suite 300  
San Francisco, CA 94104  
USA

### Privacy Policy Updates

This Privacy Statement is a living document. As part of the Blurb Terms and Conditions, this Privacy Policy is subject to reasonable amendments, for example to fulfill new and applicable statutory requirements and regulations or in case of new services, in accordance with the terms of the Terms and Conditions. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy that expand our rights to use your Personal Information, we will notify you to seek your consent either through email, or a prominent posting on our Website, or as otherwise required by law. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
